NATHANIEL POPPER , AUTHOR OF  DIGITAL COLD,REPORTER, NEW YORK TIMES ,SAN FRANSISCO
NATHANIEL POPPER、DIGITAL COLDの著者、ニューヨークタイムズ、サンフランシスコ ビットコインは、まず2008年に登場しました。
Bitcoin first emerged in 2008. The initial paper and software
最初の論文とソフトウェアが、
came from someone going by the name of Satoshi Nakamoto.
なかもと　さとし という 名前の 誰かにより、提供されました。
The idea behind the system was
システムの背後にある 考え方はなにかというと
that it would be a final network outside of the control of government.
政府のコントロールの外、
outside of control of Banks.
銀行のコントロールの外側にある、 金融ネットワークであるということです。
And it would do this by creating a sort of network.
そして、インターネットのように、
much like the internet that was run by people actually using the currency.
その仮想通貨の利用者間のネットワークをつなぐことで 作られる金融ネットワークです。
in 2011, a series of booms and busts overtook
2011年に、BitCointは、様々な好調と不調を乗り越え
the bitcoin and brought it into public consciousness.
一般の人々に意識され始めました。
Like any utopian technology, bitcoin has  really run up against
そのなかで、他の ユートピア的な技術と同様に、理想を追い求め
the outer limits of what it's trying to do.
ビットコインは 既存の壁に本当にぶつかり続けました。
as it has  spread around the world.
そのようにしながら世界中に広がっていったのです。
TRUST DISRUPTED BITCOIN AND THE BLOCKCHAIN TechCrunch Originals
信用の破壊 ビットコインとブロックチェイン TechCrunch Originals
1. In the Begining
1.始まり
january 3,2009 : Date first Bitcoins released
2009年1月3日：最初のビットコインがリリースされた日
january 3,2009: Date first Bitcoins released 2140: year that last Bitcoin will be released.
2140年 ：最後ののビットコインがリリースされる年
Bitcoin Mine Undisclosed Location Caracas, Venezuela
ビットコイン鉱山 未公開場所、カラカス、ベネズエラ
People tend not to understand much about Bitcoin.
みんなは、あまりBitcoinについて理解していないようだ。
what the hell it is ,how it functions.
それがいったいなんなのか。どうやって機能しているのか。
And they dont get that it's just a file.
それは、ただのファイルであるってことを分かっていない。
a book where all the transactions that are taking place around the world are written.
世界中で行われているすべての取引が書かれている本。
And the contents of that book is public and free to access.
そしてその本の内容は、公に公開されて自由にアクセス可能なんだ。
And the good thing, the wonderful thing, the revolutionary thing,
そしてそれの もっとも、良くて、素晴らしくて、革命的で
the groundbreaking thing of all this is
画期的なのは、
that the book is being writte by everyone - in consensus.
その本は参加者みんなによって、書かれているということ、 なんだ。
Imagine there are a few people who love a book, like, i dont know, lets say
想像してみてくれ、 なにか本がすきな人たちがいる。例えば、
Lets reach some sort of consenss about the Christians, the Bible, that kind of thing,
キリスト教についての、みんなの同意、コンセンサス、を本にすると聖書になる。
or ,say a consensus about the Jews, the Torah
例えば、ユダヤ教のコンセンサス だったら トーラーの書さ。
We are taking about a book in which
すなわちBitconでは、その本とは、
all the finacial users reach a consensus
すべての Bitcoinユーザーが合意に達した本 ってことになる。
and in a way that we can all agree on what was written there,
私たちみんながそこに書かれた内容に 同意することができるようになっていて
and everyone can constantly check it.
誰もが常にそれを確認することができます。
That is exactly what Btcoin is
それがまさに、Bitcoinなんだ。
The first time in the history of humanity that we all agree,
我々は人類の歴史で初めて、
in a technological way,
テクノロジーを使って、みんなで作り
to make something together, something we all agree on.
そしてみんなで同意するものをつくったのです。
That is a paradigm shift, which gives humanity this idea of widespread coming together.
これがパラダイムシフトなのです。 広く分散されたものが協調するという 考え方を人類に与えたのです。
We are going to insist that it works
我々は、このやり方がうまくいくと強く思います。
in a decentralized way.
分散化されたやり方で、です。
The future is brilliant.
未来は素晴らしいですよ。
Never before was someone able to put it together in a real real system, a software system.
それまで、だれも 実際にソフトウエアやシステムの でそれを実現することはできませんでした。
BOBBY LEE,CEO,BTCC,BITCOIN EXCHANGE AND MINING COMPANY,SHANGHAI because a double spending was a  biggest thing you could not  overcome.
BOBBY LEE、CEO、BTCC、ビットコイン取引所/鉱山、上海 なぜなら、二重支払が解決できない最大の問題でしたから。
With a gold , it is easier.something phisical is easy. I give you a piece of gold.
金（きん）だったら、非常に簡単です 私が、あなたに、金を渡します。
you have it. I dont have it . because i gave it to you.
すると、あなたはそれを持っています。 そして、私はそれを持っていません。
With digital information, i give you a digital photograph.
デジタル情報では、 私はあなたのデジタル写真を与えます。
In a essense, I give you a copy of it.
基本的に、私はあなたに それのコピーを与えるだけです。
when i give it to you, you have it. and I also have it.
私はあなたにそれを与えると、 あなたはそれを持っています。 しかし、私もそれを持っています。
With currecy and  digital money, we cannot allow for that.
通貨やデジタルのお金、私たちはそれを 許すことはできません。
If we did allow for that,then it's  practically useless, right?
我々はそのを許してしまうと 意味がありませんからね。
So, how do you solve that problem?
だから、どのようにその問題を解決するのか。
Researchers were looking  for that last 20-40 years.
研究者は、20から40年それを 探していました。
And finally ,in 2008 and 2009,
そしてついに、 2008年と2009年で、
We have a version of Bitcon that solve the problem.
その問題を解決したBitcoinが 使用できるようになったのです。
through the notion of global ledger  called blockchain.
ブロックチェインと呼ばれるグローバルな勘定元帳という概念によって。
Blockchain is a buss word.
Blockchainは, はやり言葉です。
GAVIN ANDERESEN,CHIEF SCENTIST, BITCOIN FOUNDATION so , I am not entirely sure what it means. I think It's entirely depends on the speaker.
GAVIN ANDERESEN、CHIEF SCENTIST、ビットコインFOUNDATION だから、私は 正確に何を意味しているか分かりませんし、話す人によって違うと思います。
In general , I think,when they say Blockchain. They mean the idea of
一般的に、私は彼らがブロックチェインと言うときは、
a record of transactions, that's secure and distributed.
セキュアに分散された取引記録のあつまりを 意味すると思います。
FRED WILSON,CO-FOUNDER,UNION SQUARE VENTURES,NEW YORK Where we sit Today, companies like Facebook, Google , Amazon, Apple,
FRED WILSON、共同創設者、UNION SQUARE VENTURES、NEW YORK フェイスブック、グーグル、アマゾン、アップルのような大企業
They are increasingly sitting on all of our data.
彼らは ますます私たちの大事なデータを取り扱っています。
Everytime somebody *en-masses* big monopolies
独占支配をはじめるといつもあることが起きます。
Something comes along that's just completely and totaly a game changer.
完全に世界を変えてしまうゲームチェンジャーがやってくるのです。
And I think it's blockchain technology.
そして、私はそれがブロックチェイン技術だと思います。
VITALIK BUTERIN,FOUNDER,ETHEREUM,TORONTO,MOSCOW,SHANGHAI It is a buss word and but at the same time, the word refers to a paticular thing.
VITALIK BUTERIN、創始者、イーサリアム、トロント、モスクワ、上海 それは はやり言葉で、しかし同時に、 その言葉があること事を意味します。
the particular thing is really useful and you can a lot of stuff on it.
そのあるものは本当に便利で、あなたはそれで 沢山のものをつくることができます。
There are lot of ways to describe it.
それを表現する言い方はたくさんありますが、
like one phrase that Robert Sams has used ,that I really like, is Decentralized automation.
私は、ロバート・サムスの言ったフレーズが好きです。 分散型自動化 です。
So, the idea you can ,sort of , run various kinds of processes in a way that number one is completely automated.
これはどういう考え方かというと、 様々な処理を２つのやり方で実行するということです。 １つは、完全に自動化されている。
So you  get just  huge gains in efficiency out of that.
だから、効率性から大きなメリットを 得ることができます。
And the number two is  that decentralized which means that
そして、2つ目は、分散化です。
No1. Like there is no sort of process that can get corrupted by one particular entity.
一つの特定の企業や組織が、破壊できてしまうような 唯一のプロセスがあるわけではないこと。
And No2. there is no process that just requires a central entity and then
そのおかげで処理自体が、 集権化された組織を必要としないので、
sort of natural *yield* creates too much oppotunity for that central entity to become a monopoly.
その組織による独占的な機会の不均等を 防ぐことができます。
and by that I  mean, distributed ledger rather than bitcoin.
むしろビットコインよりも、分散台帳と ブロックチェインという部分を大事だと考えています。
moves are away from the founding principle of Bitcoin
匿名性を重要視しているBitcoinの原則から離れ、
around anonymity and replaces it with certain known actors.
代わりに 特定できる参加者を入ってもらいます。
With regulated finacial systems.
そして既存の 規制の入った金融のシステムとの連携する。
But , none of that , inevitablly means anything.
しかし、それは実は、将来的に、何の意味もなくなるのは避けられないでしょう。
Here is a way I would say , People always overestimate what technology can do in 2 years, but  underestimate what it can do in 10.
ここで私は、言いたいのは、 人々は常に2年間でテクノロジーができることを過大評価 するが、10年でできることは 過小評価する。ということです。
LARRY SUMMERS, FORMER SECURETARY OF TREASURY USA People who think somehow the Bitcoin is gonna
LARRY　SUMMERS、元アメリカ財務省長官 どうもBitcoinが自由主義者のパラダイスを実現すると
bring in some Libertarian paradise where we are not going to have KNOW YOUR CUSTOMER rules
そこでは、 ”顧客を知る”(KYC)ルールが 存在しなかったり、
and not going to have rules on Money transfer. That will not happen.
と送金に関する規則がないようなことがおきると 思っている人がいるようですが、 それが起こることはありません。
People who think that  all the currencies are going to be depotched and gonna have a hyper inflation.
すべての通貨は、いつかハイパーインフレになるので、
Bitcoin is salvation . I thnk they are wrong too.
ビットコインがその救いとなると思っている人もいるようですが。 私は、彼らも間違っていると考えます。
in a world where we've got a real struggle to get up to 2 percent inflation.
2％インフレを 保持するために 努力している
Anywhere industrial world. But,
産業世界にいるのです。
is the Blockchain technology gonna be  fundamental to reducing  fractions ?
しかし、ブロックチェーンが 今後  取引の 不効率をなくす 基礎技術となるのか？
I think  the answer is overwelmingly likely  that it is going to be  Yes.
その答えは、圧倒される気持ちをもちつつ、 イエス答えます。
ROGER VER,EARLY BITCOIN EVANGELIST, TOKYO Larry Summers was talking about how blockchain is here to stay
ROGER VER、初期のビットコインエバンジェリスト、東京 ラリー・サマーズが ブロックチェーンがいまどういう状態にあるか、
And  Bitcoin technology is amazing and this gonna change the ways that   financial system world to work.
そして、ビットコイン技術は驚くべきであり、これは、 金融システム世界の働きを変えると話していました。
but *fairly*  bitcoiners like myself think we gonna be able to have
しかし　私のような ビットコイナーは、それでも匿名の取引を が可能だと考えています。
anonymous transactions that  are private from the  government and the people are actually allowed to do what they want  with their money
それは、政府からも監視されず、人々は、自分のお金について自由に やりたいことができる。
And he said we were wrong about that. I think one of us is wrong .
そして彼は、我々はそれについて間違っていると述べました。 私たちのいずれかが間違っていることになるだろうと思います。
I dont  think it's  going to be  me.
それは、私になるだろうと思っていませんが。
I kind of knew with  that day would come in which the people that share my world view are going to   be  the  minority.
私の世界観は、ビットコインで少数派も なる日がくると 気づいていました。
In Bitcoin, but  I think that's also a sign that  we are winning
私はそれはそれで、また、我々は勝っている兆候だと思います。
Now ,this  many other people are interested in this technology.
なぜなら今、この他の多くの人がこの技術に興味を持っています。
someone seems to have shared silimar  world view to my own created. That's pretty exciting.
自分が考えた世界観と同様の世界観を誰かがもっている。 これはかなりエキサイティングです。
bank of america, Wells Fargo and western union  are here in space.
バンク・オブ・アメリカ、ウェルズ・ファーゴとウェスタンユニオンが、 我々のブロックチェインを追っかけています。
That means we are winning.
それは我々が勝利しそうな兆候だと思います。
Hopefully it means they wont able to *co-opt* what we've built so far
できることなら、彼らが、我々はこれまでに構築したものの一部だけを取り入れて、
and turn it into sort of  hierachical system in which, you know , governments are able to monitor every single transaction that people make
それを 階層的なシステムで、すべての取引を 監視するようにならないことを祈ります。
That would be my nightmare outcome.
それは　まさに 私の悪夢です。
There is now a sort of this battle between , you know, the people who originally brought this thing into the world
いま、ここには1種の 戦いがあります。 もともと、この世界に ブロックチェーンを持ち込んだ人たち、
and who wanted this  to be a sort of revolutinarily new technology that would   help   free people from governments and banks.
そして、それと、政府や銀行からのしがらみを外れて 自由に取引をするための新技術になってほしい人たち。
And now  on the other side , there are Governemts and Banks.
そして今、もう一方の側に、政府と銀行がいます。
they themselves are trying  use this technology to change the way that we use money and change the way the infomation is stored.
彼ら自身もまた、この技術を使い、お金の使い方を変え、 情報の保存の方法を変えようとしているのです。
I think it is very much an open question as to  where this ends up.
この戦いがどこの終わるのか。 それは、答えがわからない質問になるでしょう。